A Guide to the Blue Ridge Parkway Folklore Project Records, 1978-1979
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Blue Ridge Parkway Folklore Project Records, 1978-1979
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Blue Ridge Parkway Folklore Project
Ms1986-009
14 Cubic Feet 15 boxes
The collection includes records from an oral history project conducted by the American Folklife Center in cooperation with the National Park Service created between 1978 and 1979.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Blue Ridge Parkway Folklore Project Records was deposited with Special Collections in 1986.
Scope and Content
The collection includes records from an oral history project conducted by the American Folklife Center in cooperation with the National Park Service. Project surveyed folk cultural traditions along the Blue Ridge Parkway, particularly along a hundred-mile stretch from Rocky Knob, Virginia, to Doughton Park, North Carolina. Field coordinator for the project was Charles K. Wolfe of Middle Tennessee State University. The collection consists of taped interviews with residents, photographs, field notes, and some administrative records from 1978 and 1979.
Most, but not all, of the audio reels are labeled with the name of people/organization(s) interviewed. When that information is known, it is provided, along with the alpha-numeric identifier in the "Contents List" below.
Existence and Location of Originals
The Library of Congress holds an additional, more extensive collection of materials relating to the Blue Ridge Parkway Folklife Project. The finding aid for that collection is available online.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into two series.
Series I: Audio (Reels) contains audio files in their original tape formats. This series is in the original order in which is was received.
Series II: Papers (Audio Logs, Field Notes, & Research Files) consists of original and photocopied field notes, photographs, and photograph log books. It also includes some text-based audio logs. This series is in the original order in which is was received.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Local/Regional History and Appalachian South
Genre and Form Terms:
Oral histories (document genres)
Corporate Names:
Blue Ridge Parkway Folklore Project
Contents List
- Series I: Audio (Reels)
  - Marvin Lyon (2)/BR8-BO-R26 (Box 3)
  - Marvin Lyon (3)/BR8-BO-R27 (Box 3)
  - Marvin Lyon (4)/BR8-BO-R28 (Box 3)
  - Clark's Creek Progressive Primitive Baptist Church (1)/BR8-BO-R29 (Box 3)
  - Clark's Creek Progressive Primitive Baptist Church (2)/BR8-BO-R30 (Box 3)
  - Clark's Creek Progressive Primitive Baptist Church (3)/BR8-BO-R31 (Box 3)
  - Clark's Creek Progressive Primitive Baptist Church (4)/BR8-BO-R32 (Box 3)
  - Reece Billing/BR8-BO-R33 (Box 3)
  - Laurel Glen (1)/BR8-BO-R34 (Box 3)
  - Laurel Glen (2)/BR8-BO-R35 (Box 3)
  - Laurel Glen (3)/BR8-BO-R36 (Box 3)
  - Reece Billing (1)/BR8-BO-R37 (Box 3)
  - Reece Billing (2)/BR8-BO-R38 (Box 3)
  - Dewey Truitt, Molasses Making (1)/BR8-BO-R39 (Box 3)
  - Dewey Truitt, Molasses Making (2)/BR8-BO-R40 (Box 3)
  - Dewey Truitt, Molasses Making (3)/BR8-BO-R41 (Box 3)
  - Galax Livestock Sale (1)/BR8-BO-R42 (Box 3)
  - Galax Livestock Sale (2)/BR8-BO-R43 (Box 3)
  - Skyline Independent Baptist Church (1)/BR8-BO-R44 (Box 3)
  - Skyline Independent Baptist Church (2)/BR8-BO-R45 (Box 3)
  - Skyline Independent Baptist Church (3)/BR8-BO-R46 (Box 3)
  - Beech Slate (1)/BR8-BO-R47 (Box 3)
  - Slate Family (2)/BR8-BO-R48 (Box 3)
  - Slate Family (3)/BR8-BO-R49 (Box 3)
  - Fred and Litha Lowe (1)/BR8-CW-C1 (Box 3)
  - Fred and Litha Lowe (2)/BR8-CW-C2 (Box 3)
  - Fred and Litha Lowe (3)/BR8-CW-C3 (Box 3)
  - Marshall Bros. Auction; Marshall Larger Radio Show/BR8-CW-C4 (Box 3)
  - Dub of WPACE "Sat Morning Merry Go Round" live on 5-29-76, Melvin Slayden & Carolin Roebler/BR8-CW-C5 (Box 3)
  - Twin County Fox Hunt Field Trial (1)/BR8-CW-R1 (Box 4)
  - Twin County Fox Hunt Field Trial (2)/BR8-CW-R2 (Box 4)
  - Twin County Fox Hunt Field Trial (3)/BR8-CW-R3 (Box 4)
  - Awards and Meeting Field Trial (1)/BR8-CW-R4 (Box 4)
  - Awards and Meeting Field Trial (2)/BR8-CW-R5 (Box 4)
  - Friendship Independent Baptist Church Monthly Gospel Sing (1)/BR8-CW-R6 (Box 4)
  - Friendship Independent Baptist Church Monthly Gospel Sing (2)/BR8-CW-R7 (Box 4)
  - Friendship Independent Baptist Church Monthly Gospel Sing (3)/BR8-CW-R8 (Box 4)
  - Friendship Independent Baptist Church Monthly Gospel Sing (4)/BR8-CW-R9 (Box 4)
  - Friendship Independent Baptist Church Monthly Gospel Sing (5)/BR8-CW-R10 (Box 4)
  - Radio Program: Thurman Largen Family, WHHV/BR8-CW-R11 (Box 4)
  - Schuyler Family (1)/BR8-CW-R12 (Box 4)
  - Schuyler Family (2)/BR8-CW-R13 (Box 4)
  - Schuyler Family (3)/BR8-CW-R14 (Box 4)
  - Schuyler Family (4)/BR8-CW-R15 (Box 4)
  - Schuyler Family (1)/BR8-CW-R16 (Box 4)
  - Schuyler Family (2)/BR8-CW-R17 (Box 4)
  - Schuyler Family (3)/BR8-CW-R18 (Box 4)
  - Schuyler Family (4)/BR8-CW-R19 (Box 4)
  - Benlah Fiddlers Convention (1)/BR8-CW-R20 (Box 4)
  - Benlah Fiddlers Convention (2)/BR8-CW-R21 (Box 4)
  - Benlah Fiddlers Convention (3)/BR8-CW-R22 (Box 4)
  - Benlah Fiddlers Convention (4)/BR8-CW-R23 (Box 4)
  - Benlah Fiddlers Convention (5)/BR8-CW-R24 (Box 4)
  - Macedonia Baptist Church (1)/BR8-CW-R25 (Box 4)
  - Macedonia Baptist Church (2)/BR8-CW-R26 (Box 4)
  - Macedonia Baptist Church (3)/BR8-CW-R27 (Box 4)
  - Marshall Largen Family (1)/BR8-CW-R28 (Box 4)
  - Marshall Largen Family (2)/BR8-CW-R29 (Box 4)
  - Marshall Largen Family (3)/BR8-CW-R30 (Box 4)
  - Marshall Largen Family (4)/BR8-CW-R31 (Box 4)
  - Marshall Largen Family (5)/BR8-CW-R32 (Box 4)
  - Elkhorn Four (1)/BR8-CW-R33 (Box 4)
  - Elkhorn Four (2)/BR8-CW-R34 (Box 4)
  - Elkhorn Four (3)/BR8-CW-R35 (Box 4)
  - Elkhorn Four (4)/BR8-CW-R36 (Box 4)
  - Jim and Artie Marshall (1)/BR8-CW-R37 (Box 4)
  - Jim and Artie Marshall (2)/BR8-CW-R38 (Box 4)
  - [Jim and Artie Marshall (3)]/BR8-CW-R39 (Box 5)
  - [Jim and Artie Marshall (4)]/BR8-CW-R40 (Box 5)
  - Marshall (5)/BR8-CW-R41 (Box 5)
  - Sizemore Square Dance (1)/BR8-CW-R42 (Box 5)
  - Sizemore Square Dance (2)/BR8-CW-R43 (Box 5)
  - Sizemore Square Dance (3)/BR8-CW-R44 (Box 5)
  - Sizemore Square Dance (4)/BR8-CW-R45 (Box 5)
  - Sizemore Square Dance (5)/BR8-CW-R46 (Box 5)
  - Sizemore Square Dance (6)/BR8-CW-R47 (Box 5)
  - "Independent Baptist Hour," Rev. Coy Combs/BR8-CW-R48 (Box 5)
  - BR8-CW-R49 (Box 5)
  - BR8-CW-R50 (Box 5)
  - New Covenant Association Meeting (1)/BR8-CW-R51 (Box 5)
  - New Covenant Association Meeting (2)/BR8-CW-R52 (Box 5)
  - New Covenant Association Meeting (3)/BR8-CW-R53 (Box 5)
  - New Covenant Association Meeting (4)/BR8-CW-R54 (Box 5)
  - New Covenant Association Meeting (5)/BR8-CW-R55 (Box 5)
  - Full Gospel Holiness Church (1)/BR8-CW-R56 (Box 5)
  - Full Gospel Holiness Church (2)/BR8-CW-R57 (Box 5)
  - Baptising/BR8-CW-R58 (Box 5)
  - Elk Horn Four, session #2 (1)/BR8-CW-R59 (Box 5)
  - Dub. of home tapes made 1971, Thompson Family/BR8-CW-R60 (Box 5)
  - Elk Horn Four, session #2 (2)/BR8-CW-R61 (Box 5)
  - J. A. Easter (1)/BR8-CW-R62 (Box 5)
  - J. A. Easter (2)/BR8-CW-R63 (Box 5)
  - J. A. Easter (3)/BR8-CW-R64 (Box 5)
  - Fern Evans Band (Ramey Family) (1)/BR8-CW-R65 (Box 5)
  - Ramey Family (2)/BR8-CW-R66 (Box 5)
  - Ramey Family (3)/BR8-CW-R67 (Box 5)
  - Ramey Family (4)/BR8-CW-R68 (Box 5)
  - Elder Jess Higgins (1)/BR8-CW-R69 (Box 5)
  - Elder Jess Higgins (2)/BR8-CW-R70 (Box 5)
  - Elder Jess Higgins (3)/BR8-CW-R71 (Box 5)
  - Rev. and Mrs, Jess Higgins/BR8-CW-R72 (Box 5)
  - Faith Temple Mission (1)/BR8-CW-R73 (Box 5)
  - Faith Temple Mission (2)/BR8-CW-R74 (Box 5)
  - Faith Temple Mission (3)/BR8-CW-R75 (Box 5)
  - Dunnevant Family (1)/BR8-CW-R76 (Box 5)
  - Dunnevant Family (2)/BR8-CW-R77 (Box 6)
  - Dunnevant Family (3)/BR8-CW-R78 (Box 6)
  - Dunnevant Family (4)/BR8-CW-R79 (Box 6)
  - Boyden Carpenter dubs of home tapes/BR8-CW-R80 (Box 6)
  - Boyden Carpenter (1)/BR8-CW-R81 (Box 6)
  - Boyden Carpenter (2)/BR8-CW-R82 (Box 6)
  - Boyden Carpenter hope tapes Sept. 1978/BR8-CW-R83 (Box 6)
  - Tobacco auction, Mt. Airy, NC/BR8-CW-R84 (Box 6)
  - A. P. Thompson (1)/BR8-CW-R85 (Box 6)
  - A. P. Thompson (2)/BR8-CW-R86 (Box 6)
  - A. P. Thompson (3)/BR8-CW-R87 (Box 6)
  - A. P. Thompson (4)/BR8-CW-R88 (Box 6)
  - J. C. Pierce (1)/BR8-CW-R89 (Box 6)
  - J. C. Pierce (2)/BR8-CW-R90 (Box 6)
  - Buleah Fiddling Contact (6)/BR8-CW-R91 (Box 6)
  - Rafe Brady (1)/BR8-CW-R92 (Box 6)
  - Rafe Brady (2)/BR8-CW-R93 (Box 6)
  - Rafe Brady (3)/BR8-CW-R94 (Box 6)
  - Rafe Brady (4)/BR8-CW-R95 (Box 6)
  - Rafe Brady (5)/BR8-CW-R96 (Box 6)
  - Jim Marshal/BR8-CW-R97 (Box 6)
  - Thelma Melton/BR8-GJ-R1 (Box 7)
  - Edna Pierce (1)/BR8-GJ-R2 (Box 7)
  - Edna Pierce (2)/BR8-GJ-R3 (Box 7)
  - Edna Pierce (3)/BR8-GJ-R4 (Box 7)
  - Edna Pierce (4)/BR8-GJ-R5 (Box 7)
  - Edna Pierce (5)/BR8-GJ-R6 (Box 7)
  - "Foot Washing," "Dinner on the Ground," Primitive Baptist Church/BR8-GJ-R7 (Box 7)
  - May Willey (1)/BR8-GJ-R8 (Box 7)
  - May Willey (2)/BR8-GJ-R9 (Box 7)
  - May Willey (3)/BR8-GJ-R10 (Box 7)
  - May Willey (4)/BR8-GJ-R11 (Box 7)
  - May Willey (5)/BR8-GJ-R12 (Box 7)
  - Ruth Lee (Wood) Holbrook (1)/BR8-GJ-R13 (Box 7)
  - Ruth Lee (Wood) Holbrook (2)/BR8-GJ-R14 (Box 7)
  - Ruth Lee (Wood) Holbrook (3)/BR8-GJ-R15 (Box 7)
  - Carrie Severt (1)/BR8-GJ-R16 (Box 7)
  - Carrie Severt (2)/BR8-GJ-R17 (Box 7)
  - Carrie Severt (3)/BR8-GJ-R18 (Box 7)
  - Carrie Severt (4)/BR8-GJ-R19 (Box 7)
  - Carrie Severt (5)/BR8-GJ-R20 (Box 7)
  - Thema Melton (1)/BR8-GJ-R21 (Box 7)
  - Thema Melton (2)/BR8-GJ-R22 (Box 7)
  - Thema Melton (3)/BR8-GJ-R23 (Box 7)
  - Ruth Newman (1)/BR8-GJ-R24 (Box 7)
  - Ruth Newman (2)/BR8-GJ-R25 (Box 7)
  - Ruth Newman (3)/BR8-GJ-R26 (Box 7)
  - Ruth Newman (4)/BR8-GJ-R27 (Box 7)
  - Ruth Newman (5)/BR8-GJ-R28 (Box 7)
  - Ruth Newman (6)/BR8-GJ-R29 (Box 7)
  - Quincy Higgins (1)/BR8-GJ-R30 (Box 7)
  - Quincy Higgins (2)/BR8-GJ-R31 (Box 7)
  - Quincy Higgins (3)/BR8-GJ-R32 (Box 7)
  - Quincy Higgins (4)/BR8-GJ-R33 (Box 7)
  - Mamie Lee and Leonard Bryan (1)/BR8-GJ-R34 (Box 7)
  - Mamie Lee and Leonard Bryan (2)/BR8-GJ-R35 (Box 7)
  - Crystal Cruise (1)/BR8-GJ-R36 (Box 7)
  - Crystal Cruise (2)/BR8-GJ-R37 (Box 7)
  - Crystal Cruise (3)/BR8-GJ-R38 (Box 7)
  - Crystal Cruise (4)/BR8-GJ-R39 (Box 8)
  - Crystal Cruise (5)/BR8-GJ-R40 (Box 8)
  - Crystal Cruise (6)/BR8-GJ-R41 (Box 8)
  - Crystal Cruise (7)/BR8-GJ-R42 (Box 8)
  - Margaret Jarvis (1)/BR8-GJ-R43 (Box 8)
  - Margaret Jarvis (2)/BR8-GJ-R44 (Box 8)
  - Margaret Jarvis (3)/BR8-GJ-R45 (Box 8)
  - Margaret Jarvis (4)/BR8-GJ-R46 (Box 8)
  - Carrie Severt (1)/BR8-GJ-R47 (Box 8)
  - Carrie Severt (2)/BR8-GJ-R48 (Box 8)
  - Quilting-Meadows of Dan Baptist Church (1)/BR8-GJ-R49 (Box 8)
  - Quilting-Meadows of Dan Baptist Church (2)/BR8-GJ-R50 (Box 8)
  - Quilting-Meadows of Dan Baptist Church (3)/BR8-GJ-R51 (Box 8)
  - Quilting-Meadows of Dan Baptist Church (4)/BR8-GJ-R52 (Box 8)
  - Quilting-Meadows of Dan Baptist Church (5)/BR8-GJ-R53 (Box 8)
  - Quilting-Meadows of Dan Baptist Church (6)/BR8-GJ-R54 (Box 8)
  - Quilting-Meadows of Dan Baptist Church (7)/BR8-GJ-R55 (Box 8)
  - Quilting-Meadows of Dan Baptist Church (8)/BR8-GJ-R56 (Box 8)
  - Roxie Ray (1)/BR8-GJ-R57 (Box 8)
  - Roxie Ray (2)/BR8-GJ-R58 (Box 8)
  - Roxie Ray (3)/BR8-GJ-R59 (Box 8)
  - Roxie Ray (4)/BR8-GJ-R60 (Box 8)
  - New Covenant Baptist Association; Redmond Creek Baptist Church, Galax, Va/BR8-GJ-R61 (Box 8)
  - Stone Mountain Craft Shop (1)/BR8-GJ-R62 (Box 8)
  - Stone Mountain Craft Shop (2)/BR8-GJ-R63 (Box 8)
  - Ruth Holbrook (1)/BR8-GJ-R64 (Box 8)
  - Ruth Holbrook (2)/BR8-GJ-R65 (Box 8)
  - Ruth Holbrook (3)/BR8-GJ-R66 (Box 8)
  - Ruth Holbrook (4)/BR8-GJ-R67 (Box 8)
  - Alma Hemmings (1)/BR8-GJ-R68 (Box 8)
  - Alma Hemmings (2)/BR8-GJ-R69 (Box 8)
  - Alma Hemmings (3)/BR8-GJ-R70 (Box 8)
  - Quilting Group, Poplar Springs (1)/BR8-GJ-R71 (Box 8)
  - Quilting Group, Poplar Springs (2)/BR8-GJ-R72 (Box 8)
  - Quilting Group, Poplar Springs (3)/BR8-GJ-R73 (Box 8)
  - Quilting Group, Poplar Springs (4); Roxie Ray/BR8-GJ-R74 (Box 8)
  - Roxie Ray (5)/BR8-GJ-R75 (Box 8)
  - Roxie Ray (6)/BR8-GJ-R76 (Box 8)
  - Mazie Beamer (1)/BR8-GJ-R77 (Box 9)
  - Mazie Beamer (2)/BR8-GJ-R78 (Box 9)
  - Mazie Beamer (3)/BR8-GJ-R79 (Box 9)
  - Mazie Beamer (4)/BR8-GJ-R80 (Box 9)
  - Quilting-Meadows of Dan Baptist Church (9)/BR8-GJ-R81 (Box 9)
  - Quilting-Meadows of Dan Baptist Church (10)/BR8-GJ-R82 (Box 9)
  - Mrs. Elizabeth Smith/BR8-GJ-R83 (Box 9)
  - Elizabeth Smith (2)/BR8-GJ-R84 (Box 9)
  - Elizabeth Smith (3)/BR8-GJ-R85 (Box 9)
  - BR8-GJ-R86 (Box 9)
  - BR8-GJ-R87 (Box 9)
  - Fern Evans (3)/BR8-GJ-R88 (Box 9)
  - Ela Patton (1)/BR8-GJ-R89 (Box 9)
  - Ela Patton (2)/BR8-GJ-R90 (Box 9)
  - Ela Patton (3)/BR8-GJ-R91 (Box 9)
  - Mrs. Donna Choate (1)/BR8-GJ-R92 (Box 9)
  - Donna Choate (2)/BR8-GJ-R93 (Box 9)
  - Donna Choate (3)/BR8-GJ-R94 (Box 9)
  - Nora Virginia Glasco (1)/BR8-GJ-R95 (Box 9)
  - Nora Virginia Glasco (2)/BR8-GJ-R96 (Box 9)
  - Nora Virginia Glasco (3)/BR8-GJ-R97 (Box 9)
  - Nora Virginia Glasco (4)/BR8-GJ-R98 (Box 9)
  - Zenna Todd (1)/BR8-GJ-R99 (Box 9)
  - Zenna Todd (2)/BR8-GJ-R100 (Box 9)
  - Zenna Todd (3)/BR8-GJ-R101 (Box 9)
  - Zenna Todd (4)/BR8-GJ-R102 (Box 9)
  - Mrs. Maggie Everett (1)/BR8-GJ-R103 (Box 9)
  - Mrs. Maggie Shockley (2)/BR8-GJ-R104 (Box 9)
  - Mrs. Lura B. Stanley (1)/BR8-GJ-R105 (Box 9)
  - BR8-GJ-R106 (Box 9)
  - BR8-GJ-R107 (Box 9)
  - BR8-GJ-R108 (Box 9)
  - BR8-GJ-R109 (Box 9)
  - Berlie Largen (2)/BR8-GJ-R110 (Box 9)
  - Taylor Kemble (1)/BR8-PM-C1A (Box 9)
  - Taylor Kemble (2)/BR8-PM-C1B (Box 9)
  - Taylor Kemble (3)/BR8-PM-C2 (Box 9)
  - Matt Burnett (copy)/BR8-PM-R1C (Box 10)
  - Matt Burnett/BR8-PM-R2C (Box 10)
  - Will Barnard/BR8-PM-R3C (Box 10)
  - Will Barnard/BR8-PM-R4 (Box 10)
  - Will Barnard/BR8-PM-R5 (Box 10)
  - Will Barnard/BR8-PM-R6 (Box 10)
  - Will Barnard/BR8-PM-R7 (Box 10)
  - Herbert Fulk (1)/BR8-PM-R8 (Box 10)
  - Herbert Fulk (2)/BR8-PM-R9 (Box 10)
  - Herbert Fulks/BR8-PM-R10 (Box 10)
  - Hatcher/BR8-PM-R11 (Box 10)
  - Hatcher (2)/BR8-PM-R12 (Box 10)
  - Hatcher/BR8-PM-R13 (Box 10)
  - Florence Creek (1)/BR8-PM-R14 (Box 10)
  - Florence Creek (2)/BR8-PM-R15 (Box 10)
  - Fred Clifton/BR8-PM-R16 (Box 10)
  - Fred Clifton/BR8-PM-R17 (Box 10)
  - Fred Clifton/BR8-PM-R18 (Box 10)
  - McKinley Brim/BR8-PM-R19 (Box 10)
  - McKinley Brim/BR8-PM-R20 (Box 10)
  - McKinley Brim/BR8-PM-R21 (Box 10)
  - Ruth Holbrook/BR8-PM-R22 (Box 10)
  - Ruth Holbrook (2)/BR8-PM-R23 (Box 10)
  - Claude Kenedy (1)/BR8-PM-R24 (Box 10)
  - Claude Kenedy (2)/BR8-PM-R25 (Box 10)
  - Ben "Jr" Harris/BR8-PM-R26 (Box 10)
  - Ben "Jr" Harris (2)/BR8-PM-R27 (Box 10)
  - Ben "Jr" Harris (3)/BR8-PM-R28 (Box 10)
  - Dean Gambill (1)/BR8-PM-R29 (Box 10)
  - Dean Gambill (2)/BR8-PM-R30 (Box 10)
  - Dean Gambill (3)/BR8-PM-R31 (Box 10)
  - Dean Gambill (4)/BR8-PM-R32 (Box 10)
  - Marvin Lyon (1)/BR8-PM-R33 (Box 10)
  - Marvin Lyon (2)/BR8-PM-R34 (Box 10)
  - Marvin Lyon (3)/BR8-PM-R35 (Box 10)
  - Mamie Lee and Leonard Bryan (1)/BR8-PM-R36 (Box 10)
  - Mamie Lee and Leonard Bryan (2)/BR8-PM-R37 (Box 10)
  - Mamie Lee and Leonard Bryan (3)/BR8-PM-R38 (Box 11)
  - BR8-PM-R39 (Box 11)
  - Walter Brown (2)/BR8-PM-R40 (Box 11)
  - BR8-PM-R41 (Box 11)
  - Quincy Higgins (6)/BR8-PM-R42 (Box 11)
  - Quincy Higgins (7)/BR8-PM-R43 (Box 11)
  - Quincy Higgins (8)/BR8-PM-R44 (Box 11)
  - Harrison Hensley (1)/BR8-PM-R45 (Box 11)
  - Harrison Hensley (2)/BR8-PM-R46 (Box 11)
  - Mrs. Currier's Class, 4th grade, Bluerigde Elementary/BR8-PM-R47 (Box 11)
  - Mrs. Holland's 4th Grade Class/BR8-PM-R48 (Box 11)
  - Lester and Lizzie Carter (1)/BR8-PM-R49 (Box 11)
  - Lester and Lizzie Carter (2)/BR8-PM-R50 (Box 11)
  - Lester and Lizzie Carter (3)/BR8-PM-R51 (Box 11)
  - Auction, Woolwine (1)/BR8-PM-R52 (Box 11)
  - Auction, Woolwine (2)/BR8-PM-R53 (Box 11)
  - Auction, Woolwine (3)/BR8-PM-R54 (Box 11)
  - Auction, Woolwine (4)/BR8-PM-R55 (Box 11)
  - Matt Burnett (5)/BR8-PM-R56 (Box 11)
  - BR8-PM-R57 (Box 11)
  - BR8-PM-R58 (Box 11)
  - BR8-PM-R59 (Box 11)
  - BR8-PM-R60 (Box 11)
  - BR8-PM-R61 (Box 11)
  - BR8-PM-R62 (Box 11)
  - BR8-PM-R63 (Box 11)
  - BR8-PM-R64 (Box 11)
  - BR8-PM-R65 (Box 11)
  - BR8-PM-R66 (Box 11)
  - Ernest Jarvis (1)/BR8-TA-R1 (Box 11)
  - Ernest Jarvis (2)/BR8-TA-R2 (Box 11)
  - Ernest Jarvis (3)/BR8-TA-R3 (Box 11)
  - Ernest Jarvis (4)/BR8-TA-R4 (Box 11)
  - Ernest Jarvis/BR8-TA-R5 (Box 11)
  - Roy Weddle (1)/BR8-TA-R6 (Box 11)
  - Roy Weddle (2)/BR8-TA-R7 (Box 11)
  - Roy Weddle (3)/BR8-TA-R8 (Box 11)
  - Wrestling/BR8-TA-R9 (Box 11)
  - Sense of Time I/Blue Ridge Selections- 1 (Box 12)
  - Sense of Time II/Blue Ridge Selections- 2 (Box 12)
  - Sense of Time III/Blue Ridge Selections- 3 (Box 12)
  - Sense of Place I/Blue Ridge Selections- 4 (Box 12)
  - Sense of Place II/Blue Ridge Selections- 5 (Box 12)
  - Sense of Place III/Blue Ridge Selections- 6 (Box 12)
  - Traditional Social Life I/Blue Ridge Selections- 7 (Box 12)
  - Traditional Social Life II/Blue Ridge Selections- 8 (Box 12)
  - Religious Expression I/Blue Ridge Selections- 9 (Box 12)
  - Religious Expression II/Blue Ridge Selections- 10 (Box 12)
  - Religious Expression III/Blue Ridge Selections- 11 (Box 12)
  - Religious Expression IV/Blue Ridge Selections- 12 (Box 12)
  - Crossroads Primitive Baptist Church (1)/BR8-CF-R1 (Box 14)
  - Crossroads Primitive Baptist Church (2)/BR8-CF-R2 (Box 14)
  - Crossroads Primitive Baptist Church (3)/BR8-CF-R3 (Box 14)
  - Crossroads Primitive Baptist Church (4)/BR8-CF-R4 (Box 14)
  - Crossroads Primitive Baptist Church (5)/BR8-CF-R5 (Box 14)
  - Iroler Fox Hunt (1)/BR8-CF-R6 (Box 14)
  - Iroler Fox Hunt (3)/BR8-CF-R7 (Box 14)
  - Iroler Fox Hunt (3)/BR8-CF-R8 (Box 14)
  - Iroler Fox Hunt (4)/BR8-CF-R9 (Box 14)
  - Mitchell's Mill (1)/BR8-CF-R11 (Box 14)
  - Mitchell's Mill (2)/BR8-CF-R10 (Box 14)
  - Dix Freeman (1)/BR8-MO-R7 (Box 14)
  - Dix Freeman (2)/BR8-MO-R8 (Box 14)
  - Clinton Ioler/BR8-MO-R13 (Box 14)
  - E. G. Branscome, Jr./BR8-MO-R14 (Box 14)
  - Elder Jess Higgins; Galax Rodeo Show; Singing; Preaching/BR8-CF-R13 (Box 14)
  - Elder Jess Higgins, "Sovereign Grace Hour," Dec 17, 1978/BR8-CF-R14 (Box 14)
  - Elder Jess Higgins; Rodeo Show/BR8-CF-R15 (Box 14)
  - BR8-TE-R3 (Box 15)
  - BR8-TE-R2 (Box 15)
  - BR8-TE-R1 (Box 15)
  - Fred Clifton (1)/BR8-GP-R1 (Box 15)
  - Fred Clifton (2)/BR8-GP-R2 (Box 15)
  - Elmer Lyon (1)/BR8-RM-R1 (Box 15)
  - Elmer Lyon (2)/BR8-RM-R2 (Box 15)
  - Elmer Lyon (3)/BR8-RM-R3 (Box 15)
  - Mr. and Mrs. I. C. Weddle; Ollie Mae Weddle (Mother) (1)/BR8-RM-R4 (Box 15)
  - Weddle Family (2)/BR8-RM-R5 (Box 15)
  - Fancy Gap Elementary School Dance (1)/BR8-MO-R1 (Box 15)
  - Fancy Gap Elementary School Dance (2)/BR8-MO-R2 (Box 15)
  - Fairview Dance (1)/BR8-MO-R3 (Box 15)
  - Fairview Dance (2)/BR8-MO-R4 (Box 15)
  - Fancy Gap Dance (1)/BR8-MO-R5 (Box 15)
  - Fancy Gap Dance (2)/BR8-MO-R6 (Box 15)
  - Bertie Wright/BR8-CF-R12 (Box 15)
- Series II: Papers (Audio Logs, Field Notes, & Research Files)
  - Audio Logs (Box 1)
  - Audio Logs- AFLC RP: Macnow, Wally; Mullen, Patrick; Adler, Thomas (Box 1)
  - Audio Logs- AFLC RP: Eiler, Terry; Johnson, Geraldine (Box 1)
  - Audio Logs- AFLC RP: Johnson, Geraldine Part II (Box 1)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Parkway Folklife Project: Field Notes- Blanton Owen (Box-folder 2-1)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Parkway Folklife Project: Field Notes- Charles Wolfe (Box-folder 2-2)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Parkway Folklife Project: Field Notes- Howard Marshall (Box-folder 2-3)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Parkway Folklife Project: Field Notes- Patrick Mullen (Box-folder 2-4)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Parkway Folklife Project: Field Notes- Thomas Adler (Box-folder 2-5)
  - Field Notes- Manuscript draft, several authors (Box-folder 2-6)
  - Geraldine N. Johnson, "Blue Ridge Quilts- Plain and Fancy" (Box-folder 2-7)
  - Geraldine N. Johnson- Field Notes (Box-folder 2-8)
  - Margaret C. Owen, "Dance Traditions in the Blue Ridge" (Box-folder 2-9)
  - Margaret C. Owen, Field Notes- photocopy (Box-folder 2-10)
  - Oral Data Obtained 8/18/78 re: D.M. Akers Farmstead (Box-folder 2-11)
  - Patrick B. Mullen, "Ritual and Sacred Narratives in the Blue Ridge Mountains" (Box-folder 2-12)
  - Thomas Adler, "Towards an Ecology of Folk Housing in the East Central Blue Ridge (Box-folder 2-13)
  - Blue Ridge Parkway Folklife Project (Box-folder 13-1)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Parkway Folklife Project B&W Contacts: Master List (Box-folder 13-2)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 1- B&W Contacts: 20103, 20114, 20141, 20154 (Box-folder 13-3)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 2- B&W Contacts: 20169, 20170, 20171 (Box-folder 13-4)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 3- B&W Contacts: 20189, 20190, 20198 (Box-folder 13-5)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 4- B&W Contacts: 20202, 20203, 20205 (Box-folder 13-6)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 5- B&W Contacts: 20212, 20222, 20223, 20228 (Box-folder 13-7)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 6- B&W Contacts: 20229, 20231 (Box-folder 13-8)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 7- B&W Contacts: 20232, 20236, 20255, 20256 (Box-folder 13-9)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 8- B&W Contacts: 20257, 20263 (Box-folder 13-10)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 9- B&W Contacts: 20302 (Box-folder 13-11)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 10- B&W Contacts: 20333, 20334, 20343 (Box-folder 13-12)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 11- B&W Contacts: 20344 (Box-folder 13-13)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 12- B&W Contacts: 20345, 20346 (Box-folder 13-14)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 13- B&W Contacts: 20348, 20358, 20365, 20398 (Box-folder 13-15)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 14- B&W Contacts: 20400, 20413, 20414 (Box-folder 13-16)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 15- B&W Contacts: 20421, 20422 (Box-folder 13-17)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 16- B&W Contacts: 20423, 20424 (Box-folder 13-18)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 17- B&W Contacts: 20443, 20462, 20485, 20491 (Box-folder 13-19)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 19- B&W Contacts: 20542 (Box-folder 13-21)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 18- B&W Contacts: 20492, 20493 (Box-folder 13-20)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 20- B&W Contacts: 20543 (Box-folder 13-22)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 21- B&W Contacts: 20544 (Box-folder 13-23)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 22- B&W Contacts: 20553, 20577, 20624, 20698 (Box-folder 13-24)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 23- B&W Contacts: 20776, 20777, 20822, 21124, 21215 (Box-folder 13-25)
  - 1978 Blue Ridge Folklife Project File 29- B&W Contacts: unidentified (Box-folder 13-26)
  - AFLC Research Project B&W Photo Logs, book no.1 (Box 13)
  - AFLC Research Project B&W Photo Logs, book no.2 (Box 13)